<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gabriela K Hajduk</title>
    <description>Gabriela K Hajduk&#39;s personal website</description>
    <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gkhajduk.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>ESEB 2017</title>
        <description>
          
          What a week! I’m exhausted - conferences can be so draining! It’s an incredibly intense experience when you try to make the most of it and I tried my best: I prepped for my talk, I then attended back-to-back talks in nearly all slots, and during each break and meals...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-08-26-eseb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-08-26-eseb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First PhD manuscript submitted!</title>
        <description>
          
          If you have read any of my “GWU” updates you know that I’ve been working on a beast of a manuscript. I’ve put a lot of effort into structuring it and making it easy to follow, which I saw as crucial given how much information it contains - hopefully I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-07-24-manuscript1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-07-24-manuscript1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: end June</title>
        <description>
          
          What have I been up to over the past few weeks? I had my milestone meeting - a meeting with my thesis committee to discuss progress and plans for thesis write up. It was an interesting one! I have been asked to become a student representative on a “Student Experience...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-06-28-gwu-end-June/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-06-28-gwu-end-June/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3rd Year Review Meeting</title>
        <description>
          
          What needs to be done? To pass this milestone we have to do several things. We have a new system at the University now where periodically we need to fill in an online questionnaire - the annual report and there is one linked to the final year. In addition we...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-06-14-milestone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-06-14-milestone/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: end May</title>
        <description>
          
          What have I been up to over the past few weeks? I got comments back about my manuscript - after a bit of chatting we decided to slightly adjust one of the sections. I therefore re-run the models to ensure consistency, added an extra model and then of course re-done...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-05-31-gwu-end-May/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-05-31-gwu-end-May/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: start of May</title>
        <description>
          
          What have I been up to over the past few weeks? While supervisors are working on the comments on my manuscript draft I have moved onto ironing out the next set of analyses, getting the next chapter ready for write up. The main analyses are already done, but I wanted...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-05-05-gwu-start-May/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-05-05-gwu-start-May/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork: Season 2</title>
        <description>
          
          I realised that I haven’t really published a proper fieldwork update from the last season, so here it is! This was most likely the last field season of my PhD. Photos of Oz wildlife included, so read on and enjoy :] Let’s set the scene I carry out my fieldwork...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-04-19-fieldwork2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-04-19-fieldwork2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: mid April</title>
        <description>
          
          What have I been up to over the past few weeks? The past couple of weeks I have worked on finishing the manuscript: I have sent it off for comments to my supervisors today. Yay! Really looking forward to hearing what they think. I’ve learned some things about the writing...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-04-13-gwu-mid-April/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-04-13-gwu-mid-April/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resources lists</title>
        <description>
          
          I have updated my Resources collection. It’s not complete and I will keep adding, but most tabs have at least a link or two for you to check out. You can explore: R resources from tutorials, through cheat-sheets to visualisation. LaTeX &amp;amp; Markdown resources - I popped up some thesis...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-04-11-resources/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-04-11-resources/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: end March</title>
        <description>
          
          What have I been up to over the past few weeks? The manuscript is still the main focus of my workdays. I got to the fun part of re-writing Introduction, the point where all the “meat” is already there and it’s time to add some juicy nuance to it. The...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-24-gwu-end-Mar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-24-gwu-end-Mar/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LMMs workshop - done!</title>
        <description>
          
          I ran the linear mixed effects models workshop yesterday. Since I have almost completely lost my voice I was doubly grateful for Gergana’s assistance! {Gergana is one of the people who run the Coding Club} The workshop proved popular, apparently I even broke the attendance record (we run our of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-16-LMM-workshop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-16-LMM-workshop/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to linear mixed models</title>
        <description>
          
          This is a workshop I was asked to write and teach for the Coding Club. It is aimed at people new to mixed modeling and as such it doesn’t cover all the nuances of mixed models, but hopefully serves as a starting point when it comes both to the concepts...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-09-mixed-models/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-09-mixed-models/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Go paperless! Or not</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Laptops, tablets, phones, e-readers… We are surrounded by technology and it is now possible to be paperless (to various extend, depending on your circumstances). There are more and more apps aiding with data collection and collation in the field too. Apps...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-11-fieldwork-tips-go-paperless/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-11-fieldwork-tips-go-paperless/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: mid February</title>
        <description>
          
          My talk abstract was accepted for ESEB 2017! Yay! Get ready for some superb fairy-wrens bizarreness :] What have I been up to over the past few weeks? The main focus of the past few weeks was on the content of the first PhD manuscript/chapter. This involved a bit of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-10-gwu-mid-Feb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-10-gwu-mid-Feb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Dress for Success! Part 2</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Check out also Dress for Success! Part 1, which covers materials and layering system. Short vs Long Boots Rain gear Hats Sun protection So… What do I wear? Short vs Long No matter how hot I tend to wear long trousers....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-06-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-06-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Dress for Success! Part 1</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Check out also Dress for Success! Part 2 for some extra info. It’s a fairly technical one, so the gist is below. I still come across students coming to do fieldwork on the shore wearing jeans and ankle-high wellies or even...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-05-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-05-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>General work update (GWU): mid January</title>
        <description>
          
          I said I would try to post more regular updates about everyday PhDing, but I haven’t… Here it goes. All will be tagged with everyday PhDing. What have I been up to over the past two* weeks? Planned what needs to get done this year, as it is the last...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-13-gwu-mid-Jan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-13-gwu-mid-Jan/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2017 goals: Work &amp; Personal</title>
        <description>
          
          I have reflected on 2016 on both the Work and Personal fronts, so it’s time for some goals for this year. Work Present at an international conference. Write the bulk of my thesis: I’m hoping for 4-5 chapters (if everything goes smoothly I’ll try for more as we are not...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-08-goals/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-08-goals/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking back at 2016: Work Edition</title>
        <description>
          
          Turns out that it’s actually harder to quantify my work achievements than it is to reflect on the personal side of things. In and around the office Out of the office Oddball items Low Points In and around the office I did a bunch of analysis, which hopefully should allow...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-07-looking-back-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-07-looking-back-work/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking back at 2016: Personal Edition</title>
        <description>
          
          I’m glad I did this: looking back I actually managed to do a very decent amount of stuff. During the year quite a few times it felt like I was just failing miserably at all of it: falling asleep trying to read, spending more time waiting for the paint to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-03-looking-back-personal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-03-looking-back-personal/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
