<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gabriela K Hajduk</title>
    <description>Gabriela K Hajduk&#39;s personal website</description>
    <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gkhajduk.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Packing List</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. NOTE: In this post I refer to other posts in this series (using [square brackets]) - those posts don’t exist yet, I will add links to them when they appear on the site. Intro Kit has to be tailored to your...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-23-fieldwork-tips-packing-list/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-23-fieldwork-tips-packing-list/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Arrange before you go</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Many of the things listed below take much longer than you expect. Make sure you allow enough time for everything to get through. Paperwork Check your passport expiry date. For many places your passport needs to be valid for 6 months...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-17-fieldwork-tips-before-you-go/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-17-fieldwork-tips-before-you-go/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Logistics</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Depending on your position you might have to do more or less prep before the fieldwork. Typically field assistants will have a decent chunk of the infrastructure, such as accommodation, provided for them as they will be joining an existing team...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-10-fieldwork-tips-logistics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-10-fieldwork-tips-logistics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips Series</title>
        <description>
          
          Fieldwork can be hugely rewarding, fun and enjoyable. It can be easy, but it can also turn out to be tough and challenging, both physically and mentally. There are some pitfalls that everyone should know about, but a lot of people learn by trial and error. Here are some tips...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-09-26-fieldwork-tips-series/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-09-26-fieldwork-tips-series/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Migration and a new website</title>
        <description>
          
          Soon after I decided to step up my blogging game (see my previous post) a few things happened, including a friend’s blog on Blogger being deleted without any warning or explanation. All content gone forever. This was the push I needed: I’ve been thinking about building my own website for...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-08-06-migration-and-new-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-08-06-migration-and-new-website/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting PhDing back on track!</title>
        <description>
          
          I&#39;m planning on posting some fairly regular work updates. I will paint you a picture of what I&#39;ve been up to over the last few months.When I got back from fieldwork in November I had two options:(i) either write up my analyses from the first year as a manuscript and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-03-01-getting-phding-back-on-track/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-03-01-getting-phding-back-on-track/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging plans</title>
        <description>
          
          I want to step up my blogging game, I think going back to regular writing practice would be beneficial. Till now I relied on slightly bigger events - such as conferences, courses and teaching. I regarded those as more worthy of mentioning, but sometimes it feels like there aren&#39;t enough...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-27-blogging-plans/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-27-blogging-plans/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come work with me! </title>
        <description>
          
          UPDATE 2016-03-29: I have a couple of great applicants and I shall be choosing between those two. Currently waiting for a reference. Thank you everyone for your interest. Everyone who applied will be contacted shortly.&amp;nbsp;-------------------------------------------------Yes. Literally. Come work with me on the superb fairy-wrens in Australia during my next field...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-25-come-work-with-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-25-come-work-with-me/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List or Reminders Check</title>
        <description>
          
          A year ago, in January, prompted by all the new year resolutions I shared my List of Reminders with you. Those aren&#39;t resolutions or goals, but more areas of my life to which I want to pay attention, which I want to keep in check. I return to it every...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-17-list-or-reminders-check/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-17-list-or-reminders-check/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We created a monster, a #wildbum monster</title>
        <description>
          
          It started innocently enough. It always does.Yesterday evening @AnneHilborn was posting photos of questionable quality - we all have those. Those where we tried and tried and the subject is not in focus, but instead a random bit of grass or a flower is chosen by the camera as &quot;the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-12-we-created-monster-wildbum-monster/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-12-we-created-monster-wildbum-monster/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Varied sittella</title>
        <description>
          
          Varied sittella (Daphoenositta chrysoptera). Such a cool little fella! Three local birders and myself have sat down to have some food and we spotted this varied sittella and its nest. I&#39;m happy I found the nest, it&#39;s rather well camouflaged. The sittella was going back and forwards, I&#39;m pretty sure...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-04-in-between-fieldwork-varied-sittella/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-04-in-between-fieldwork-varied-sittella/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: New Holland Honeyeater</title>
        <description>
          
          They. Were. Everywhere.The study site was full of New Holland Honeyeaters (Phylidonyris novaehollandiae) chattering away, zooming around, hopping from branch to branch, feeding, flying... so active! Hard to get good photos due to all the movement, but fun to watch.Every now and then they would take a few moments to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-01-21-in-between-fieldwork-new-holland/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-01-21-in-between-fieldwork-new-holland/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Red-browed finch</title>
        <description>
          
          Red-browed finch (Neochmia temporalis) is the most common finch around Canberra. I&#39;d often see pairs of them in bushes during the day.Early in the morning I would come across little groups foraging on the ground, between the grass too.When the spring kicked-in I saw some nest-building too. It looks very...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-01-07-in-between-fieldwork-red-browed-finch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-01-07-in-between-fieldwork-red-browed-finch/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Laughing kookaburra</title>
        <description>
          
          Laughing kookaburra (Dacelo novaeguineae) - love them! They are loud and bossy, but also manage to appear very cuddly.Very entertaining to watch, I had so much fun watching them dig for worms and eat them up like they were spaghetti.We do have some issues with the ones on the study...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-12-17-in-between-fieldwork-laughing-kookaburra/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-12-17-in-between-fieldwork-laughing-kookaburra/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Koala</title>
        <description>
          
          Koalas in Canberra are extinct, which is a great shame. Tidbinbilla Nature Reserve used to have a few captive koalas, but from what I have been told all but one of them died in the big 2003 bush fires. Poor things.Some koalas have been translocated back to the reserve recently...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-12-03-in-between-fieldwork-koala/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-12-03-in-between-fieldwork-koala/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Dusky Woodswallow</title>
        <description>
          
          Dusky Woodswallow (Artamus cyanopterus). I couldn&#39;t get much closer, but they spent ageeees preening each other and I got several very cute shots of this pair. If you think that they don&#39;t look quite right for a swallow you won&#39;t be surprised to read that they are actually more closely...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-26-in-between-fieldwork-dusky-woodswallow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-26-in-between-fieldwork-dusky-woodswallow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Magpie-lark</title>
        <description>
          
          Magpie-lark (Grallina cyanoleuca). Odd critters, very boldly behaving, not scared to come up to people. Foraging in open grass a lot. Kind of reminding me of little dinosaurs.Males and females can be distinguished by markings on their heads. Pay attention to the black stripes across the eyes. Males have a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-19-in-between-fieldwork-magpie-lark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-19-in-between-fieldwork-magpie-lark/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Update: &quot;in-between fieldwork&quot; every other Thursday</title>
        <description>
          
          Me again. I have decided that for now In-between fieldwork posts with Australian wildlife will appear on Thursdays (completely arbitrary).I&#39;m currently scheduling posts for every other Thursday to gauge how much material I have and will go from there - if there is lots left over I might bump it...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-07-update-in-between-fieldwork-every-other/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-07-update-in-between-fieldwork-every-other/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Australian king parrot</title>
        <description>
          
          Those guys were easiest to spot in the late afternoon. There were some trees on my way home where they seemed to forage a lot. Their roost must have been somewhere else, as I never saw them stay there for the night and they were never there during my morning...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-05-in-between-fieldwork-australian-king/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-11-05-in-between-fieldwork-australian-king/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In-between fieldwork: Black-fronted dotterel</title>
        <description>
          
          Black-fronted dotterels (Elseyornis melanops) are not very common around Canberra and I only managed to see a pair during my visit.They were very easy too spook and didn&#39;t allow me to approach at all, every time I tried to take a step in their direction they would strut off hurriedly....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-10-30-in-between-fieldwork-black-fronted/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2015-10-30-in-between-fieldwork-black-fronted/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
