<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gabriela K Hajduk</title>
    <description>Gabriela K Hajduk&#39;s personal website</description>
    <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gkhajduk.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: end March</title>
        <description>
          
          What have I been up to over the past few weeks? The manuscript is still the main focus of my workdays. I got to the fun part of re-writing Introduction, the point where all the “meat” is already there and it’s time to add some juicy nuance to it. The...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-24-gwu-end-Mar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-24-gwu-end-Mar/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LMMs workshop - done!</title>
        <description>
          
          I ran the linear mixed effects models workshop yesterday. Since I have almost completely lost my voice I was doubly grateful for Gergana’s assistance! {Gergana is one of the people who run the Coding Club} The workshop proved popular, apparently I even broke the attendance record (we run our of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-16-LMM-workshop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-16-LMM-workshop/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to linear mixed models</title>
        <description>
          
          This is a workshop I was asked to write and teach for the Coding Club. It is aimed at people new to mixed modeling and as such it doesn’t cover all the nuances of mixed models, but hopefully serves as a starting point when it comes both to the concepts...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-09-mixed-models/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-03-09-mixed-models/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Go paperless! Or not</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Laptops, tablets, phones, e-readers… We are surrounded by technology and it is now possible to be paperless (to various extend, depending on your circumstances). There are more and more apps aiding with data collection and collation in the field too. Apps...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-11-fieldwork-tips-go-paperless/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-11-fieldwork-tips-go-paperless/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GWU: mid February</title>
        <description>
          
          My talk abstract was accepted for ESEB 2017! Yay! Get ready for some superb fairy-wrens bizarreness :] What have I been up to over the past few weeks? The main focus of the past few weeks was on the content of the first PhD manuscript/chapter. This involved a bit of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-10-gwu-mid-Feb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-10-gwu-mid-Feb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Dress for Success! Part 2</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Check out also Dress for Success! Part 1, which covers materials and layering system. Short vs Long Boots Rain gear Hats Sun protection So… What do I wear? Short vs Long No matter how hot I tend to wear long trousers....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-06-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-06-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Dress for Success! Part 1</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Check out also Dress for Success! Part 2 for some extra info. It’s a fairly technical one, so the gist is below. I still come across students coming to do fieldwork on the shore wearing jeans and ankle-high wellies or even...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-05-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-02-05-fieldwork-tips-dress-for-success-p1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>General work update (GWU): mid January</title>
        <description>
          
          I said I would try to post more regular updates about everyday PhDing, but I haven’t… Here it goes. All will be tagged with everyday PhDing. What have I been up to over the past two* weeks? Planned what needs to get done this year, as it is the last...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-13-gwu-mid-Jan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-13-gwu-mid-Jan/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2017 goals: Work &amp; Personal</title>
        <description>
          
          I have reflected on 2016 on both the Work and Personal fronts, so it’s time for some goals for this year. Work Present at an international conference. Write the bulk of my thesis: I’m hoping for 4-5 chapters (if everything goes smoothly I’ll try for more as we are not...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-08-goals/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-08-goals/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking back at 2016: Work Edition</title>
        <description>
          
          Turns out that it’s actually harder to quantify my work achievements than it is to reflect on the personal side of things. In and around the office Out of the office Oddball items Low Points In and around the office I did a bunch of analysis, which hopefully should allow...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-07-looking-back-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-07-looking-back-work/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking back at 2016: Personal Edition</title>
        <description>
          
          I’m glad I did this: looking back I actually managed to do a very decent amount of stuff. During the year quite a few times it felt like I was just failing miserably at all of it: falling asleep trying to read, spending more time waiting for the paint to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-03-looking-back-personal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2017-01-03-looking-back-personal/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Packing List</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. NOTE: In this post I refer to other posts in this series (using [square brackets]) - those posts don’t exist yet, I will add links to them when they appear on the site. Intro Kit has to be tailored to your...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-23-fieldwork-tips-packing-list/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-23-fieldwork-tips-packing-list/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Arrange before you go</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Many of the things listed below take much longer than you expect. Make sure you allow enough time for everything to get through. Paperwork Check your passport expiry date. For many places your passport needs to be valid for 6 months...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-17-fieldwork-tips-before-you-go/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-17-fieldwork-tips-before-you-go/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips: Logistics</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is part of a Fieldwork Tips series. Depending on your position you might have to do more or less prep before the fieldwork. Typically field assistants will have a decent chunk of the infrastructure, such as accommodation, provided for them as they will be joining an existing team...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-10-fieldwork-tips-logistics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-10-10-fieldwork-tips-logistics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fieldwork Tips Series</title>
        <description>
          
          Fieldwork can be hugely rewarding, fun and enjoyable. It can be easy, but it can also turn out to be tough and challenging, both physically and mentally. There are some pitfalls that everyone should know about, but a lot of people learn by trial and error. Here are some tips...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-09-26-fieldwork-tips-series/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-09-26-fieldwork-tips-series/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Migration and a new website</title>
        <description>
          
          Soon after I decided to step up my blogging game (see my previous post) a few things happened, including a friend’s blog on Blogger being deleted without any warning or explanation. All content gone forever. This was the push I needed: I’ve been thinking about building my own website for...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-08-06-migration-and-new-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-08-06-migration-and-new-website/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting PhDing back on track!</title>
        <description>
          
          I&#39;m planning on posting some fairly regular work updates. I will paint you a picture of what I&#39;ve been up to over the last few months.When I got back from fieldwork in November I had two options:(i) either write up my analyses from the first year as a manuscript and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-03-01-getting-phding-back-on-track/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-03-01-getting-phding-back-on-track/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging plans</title>
        <description>
          
          I want to step up my blogging game, I think going back to regular writing practice would be beneficial. Till now I relied on slightly bigger events - such as conferences, courses and teaching. I regarded those as more worthy of mentioning, but sometimes it feels like there aren&#39;t enough...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-27-blogging-plans/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-27-blogging-plans/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come work with me! </title>
        <description>
          
          UPDATE 2016-03-29: I have a couple of great applicants and I shall be choosing between those two. Currently waiting for a reference. Thank you everyone for your interest. Everyone who applied will be contacted shortly.&amp;nbsp;-------------------------------------------------Yes. Literally. Come work with me on the superb fairy-wrens in Australia during my next field...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-25-come-work-with-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-25-come-work-with-me/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List or Reminders Check</title>
        <description>
          
          A year ago, in January, prompted by all the new year resolutions I shared my List of Reminders with you. Those aren&#39;t resolutions or goals, but more areas of my life to which I want to pay attention, which I want to keep in check. I return to it every...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-17-list-or-reminders-check/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gkhajduk.github.io/2016-02-17-list-or-reminders-check/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
